<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools" tools:ignore="MissingTranslation">

    <string-array name="hifdh_tips">

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Strive for utmost sincerity.
            Regularly renew your intention for memorising the #Quran.
            You\'re not in this to show off or for worldly gains.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Repetition, repetition, repetition.
            There are no shortcuts to memorising the #Quran.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Practice, practice, practice.
            Continuously going over and reviewing what you have memorised is the only way to keep it strong.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Dedicate at least 30 minutes every day for memorising and revising the #Quran.
            This is easily possible.
            Remember that there are people who recite and review the #Quran for several hours a day.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Begin your memorisation journey with a small and realistic goal.
            Build upon it steadily.
            Moderation is better than a goal that causes you to give up.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            #MultipleFronts:
            Continue to learn the proper pronunciation of the Arabic letters
            but do not let this stop you from memorising.
            Work on both simultaneously.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            #MultipleFronts:
            Continue to learn the rules of recitation
            but do not let this stop you from memorising.
            Work on both simultaneously.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            #Taqwa:
            Protect your eyes from looking at that which is impermissible.
            Protect your tongue from saying that which is sinful.
            Be conscious of Allah and Allah will teach you.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            #Tawakkul:
            Memorising and keeping hold of the #Quran is a monumental task for sure
            but do your best
            – put in the time and the concentration –
            and know that Allah will take care of the rest.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            #DayInDayOut:
            Never let a day go by in which you do not revise some #Quran.
            Regardless of your weekly or monthly revision target,
            have a minimum amount that you absolutely must revise every day.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            #Constancy:
            If you fall short of your memorisation or revision target on a given day,
            force yourself to do a little extra the next day to compensate.
            Give yourself no scope to slack and decline.
        </item>

        <!--
           - Inspired by a 3-minute Nouman Ali Khan video on the "Quran Weekly" YouTube channel
           - entitled "Seek Refuge with Allah from Satan [Juz 14]"
           -->
        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Clear your environment from distractions
            and genuinely – with full presence of mind –
            seek refuge in Allah from Satan, the accursed,
            as you begin your recitation of the #Quran.
        </item>

        <!--
           - Inspired by a 3-minute Nouman Ali Khan video on the "Quran Weekly" YouTube channel
           - entitled "Seek Refuge with Allah from Satan [Juz 14]"
           -->
        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Seek Allah\'s protection from Satan, the accursed, as you begin your recitation.
            Know that he will make every attempt to corrupt your experience with the #Quran,
            to distract and deter you from it, and to suggest meanings that are just not there.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Your mobile device is a source of good for sure,
            but sometimes it\'s best to put it to the side – out of reach –
            and engage with a paper copy of the #Quran, distraction free.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Make a habit of listening to the #Quran being recited.
            Doing so will engrave it into your heart and mind,
            and will help you catch any mistakes in your memorisation.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Listen to the #Quran being recited using an app or website
            that can repeat each verse a number of times.
            As each verse repeats,
            test yourself and anticipate which verse will follow next.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Record your recitation of the #Quran and listen to the recording.
            This will help you find mistakes and improve your articulation of the verses.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Read the translation of each verse that you memorise and try to connect the words with their meanings.
            Understanding the meanings of the words will help you remember them better.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Use the same Mus-haf (printed copy of the #Quran) whenever you memorise and revise.
            This will help you visually recall where particular verses begin and end.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Recite aloud.
            This will help you catch mistakes that you would otherwise miss when reciting silently.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Memorise consecutive parts of the #Quran rather than jumping around.
            This will make it easier for you to regularly go through and review what you know.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            There is no best time for memorising and revising the #Quran that applies to everyone.
            Nevertheless, the most recommended time is after the #Fajr prayer.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Memorise with others.
            Recite what you know and what you\'re learning to a teacher, family member or friend regularly.
            And have them to recite to you.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Make a habit of writing out the verses that you have memorised on paper.
            This is one of the best ways to test what you have memorised
            and to move it from short-term to long-term memory.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Recite the verses of the #Quran that you have memorised in your prayers.
            Be bold and avoid reciting the same verses again and again in every prayer.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Recite what you have memorised in your prayer.
            It is a good way to increase your confidence in what you know.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Being in a state of purity when reciting the #Quran is highly recommended
            in order to achieve the full blessing of Allah,
            efficiency of the deed,
            and protection against the devils.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Before learning a new verse,
            recite the last few words of the previous verse.
            This will help you better remember the connection between verses.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Make a commitment to learn Arabic.
            This will help you learn verses faster,
            remember them better
            and understand them on a deeper level.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Have a plan to regularly go over all of the verses that you have memorised.
            For example, once a week or once a month depending on how much you know.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Beware of reviewing your memorisation at rapid speed simply for the sake of completion.
            Concentrate and reflect on the meanings of the verses that you recite.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Memorise the #Quran such that you can read it in a calm and measured pace.
            Anyone who can read it slowly can read it fast when needed.
            However, those who have memorised it fast will struggle when they try to slow down.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Teach what you know.
            What you teach will stick in your mind.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            When revising a page, recite it at least once without looking at the Mus-haf
            (printed copy of the #Quran).
            This will strengthen your memory and decrease your dependence on the Mus-haf.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            #Sleep:
            Get the balance right.
            Both too much and too little sleep leads to laziness and a lack of productivity.
            Respect your body and remember: a healthy body is a healthy mind.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            #Food:
            Eat right.
            Not looking after your body will lead to laziness, weight gain and health issues;
            all of which will negatively impact your memorisation.
            Respect your body and remember: a healthy body is a healthy mind.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            #Exercise:
            Healthy and frequent exercise increases the flow of blood everywhere in the body,
            including the brain.
            And an increased flow of blood means more oxygen, more energy and better thinking!
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Keep a Mus-haf (printed or digital copy of the #Quran) with you.
            Use any opportunities you get when walking, travelling or waiting around
            to make progress with your memorisation.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Make a habit of asking Allah to bless you and to grant you sincerity in your #Hifdh journey.
            In #Dua is your success.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Make a habit of asking Allah to aid you in learning, understanding and keeping hold of the #Quran.
            In #Dua is your empowerment.
        </item>

    </string-array>

</resources>
