<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools" tools:ignore="MissingTranslation">

    <string-array name="hifdh_tips">

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Strive for utmost sincerity.
            Regularly renew your intention.
	        You\'re not in this to show off or for worldly gains.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Repetition, repetition, repetition.
            There are no shortcuts in memorising the #Quran.
            Continuous repetition is key.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Dedicate at least 30 minutes every day for memorising the #Quran.
            This is easily possible.
            Remember that there are people who recite and review the #Quran for several hours a day.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Begin your memorisation journey with a small and realistic goal.
            Build upon it steadily.
            This will be more fruitful in the long run.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Learn the proper pronunciation of the Arabic letters.
            But do not let this stop you from memorising.
            Work on both simultaneously.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Protect your eyes from looking at that which is impermissible.
            Protect your tongue from saying that which is sinful.
            Be conscious of Allah and Allah will teach you.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Trust in Allah.
            Memorising and retaining the #Quran is a monumental task.
            But do your best and Allah will take care of the rest.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            If you fall short of your memorisation or revision target on a given day,
            force yourself to do a little more the next day.
            Consistency is key.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Clear your mind from any worries, problems or thoughts that will distract you.
            Seek refuge in Allah from the accursed Satan.
            Then proceed in the Name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Listening to the #Quran frequently will engrave it into your mind and heart.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Read the translation of each verse that you memorise and try to connect the words with their meanings.
            Understanding the words will help you learn and remember.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Use the same Mus-haf (i.e. printed copy of the #Quran) every time you memorise and recite.
            This will help your mind visually recall where particular verses begin and end.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Recite aloud.
            It will help you catch mistakes that you would miss when reciting in your head.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            Memorise consecutive parts of the #Quran
            rather than jumping around different parts.
            This will help you with regularly revising what you know.
        </item>

        <item>
            #HifdhTip:
            There is no best time for memorising and revising the #Quran that applies to everyone.
            Nevertheless, the most recommended time is after Fajr prayer.
        </item>

    </string-array>

</resources>
